

# **Vitaliy Sviatskiy**

Email: Telegram: Linkedin: vitalik.svt@gmail.com @tassupolnomochenzayavit linkedin.com/vitalik-svt

## Summary

Data Engineer with 6+ years of data experience.

I have Built and maintained ETL/ELT processes, Integrated large Data Sources, Automated crucial business areas, Researched and Implemented new data Tools. I have strong desire to build data platform: develop tools, architecture and DataOps processes.

#### Skills

*Primary:* Python, Airflow, SQL, Docker, Kafka, Yandex Cloud; Supportive: AWS, dbt, Big Query, PySpark, NoSQL, PowerBI;

Workflow: Agile, Jira, Confluence, Data Mesh;

Languages: Russian – C2, English – B2 (I continue to study), French – A1 (I continue to study);

## Relevant Experience

Data Engineer - Leroy Merlin - Moscow, Russia

06.2022 - Present

- Create and maintain team's ETL pipelines: handle more than 50 data pipelines, maintain team's Airflow
- Integrated large data source of website clickstream (220 million rows per hour) to DWH
- Reduced duration of existing data integration for more than 4 times using Python multithreading
- Optimize analytical SQL queries for colleagues in whole department
- Developed Python library with common functions, which reduced amount of bugs and speeded up developing
- Proposed and created on my own marts layer calculation tool (*PySpark* + *metadata*), which reduce DWH
   CPU usage, and can be used by everyone in Company with regular SQL

Data Engineer - Burger King - Moscow, Russia

09.2019 - 06.2022

- Automated one of core financial analytics area (Labour Cost) on my own initiative: Reduced time from 2
  business days of manual excel work, to 2 minutes automated calculations in database
- Enhanced data infrastructure: studied and implemented Airflow in production on my own
- Fully automated net revenue calculations for CFO. Previously, that was manual monthly-based process
- Made bunch of other automations: A/B test result calculator, Combo tax efficiency calculator, etc.

Founder - Notsobikeparts (Website, Instagram, Github) - Moscow, Russia

04.2019 - Present

- Founded operationally profitable bicycle accessories developing project
- Designed ERP/CRM SQL database with automatically calculated PnL and other reports; Currently in process
  of creation of web application (Python, Flask) for greater user experience
- Repeatedly participated as a sponsor in a local cycling events (largest was more than 1000 participants)

Business Analyst - Moscow International Airport Domodedovo

03.2017 - 09.2019

- Automated near 70% of teams excel reports with SQL (MS SQL)
- Created business process for buildings maintaining, which helps control maintaining operations 20% faster

### Education

Bauman Moscow State Technical University (<u>Lead Russian tech university</u>; <u>Anabin H+)</u>

2009 - 2015

Specialist degree (MS equivalent) in Mechanical Engineering.

Worked on cathedra while studying: it-maintenance, website moderation, lab assisting